紙牌屋
前情提要
翻譯   杏仁斯嘉麗
翻譯   國士章魚X
翻譯   蘇小黛
翻譯   吃冰棒
翻譯   草草
翻譯   Lynn_寧
時間軸   壬虛浪影
時間軸   紙袋P
后期   餓得慌
顧問   老杜
校對   草草
總監   草草
紙牌屋
人人影視傾情奉獻
第五季  第九集
安德伍德拿下俄亥俄
康威將認輸
國務卿  華盛頓
尊敬的總統先生
我謹辭去第68任國務卿職務
此致
凱瑟琳·杜蘭特
馬克·厄舍被任命為總統特別顧問
傳票
由美國國會眾議院簽發
致  尊敬的泰倫斯·烏麥克
現傳召您來眾議院紀律委員會出席聽證
日程安排
弗蘭西斯·安德伍德就職典禮
嶄露頭角的記者
在華盛頓特區慘遭地鐵事故身亡
2013年
11月5日
這樣就取決于最后一個州  俄亥俄州
It's come down to one state. Ohio.
去他的俄亥俄
Fuck Ohio.
這就是競選
This is the campaign.
我們在這個營地推銷自己
We're here at this camp selling ourselves.
我喜歡馬克  因為我總是知道他的立場
I like Mark, because I always know where he stands.
通常是對人步步緊逼
It's usually on someone's neck.
-不是我的  -馬克·厄舍不是任何人的朋友
- Not mine. - Mark Usher's no one's friend.
宣戰怎么樣
Declaration of war?
委員會  那已經完了
The committee? That's done.
你和他們想要的東西一樣
You want what they all want.
更好的地位
A better seat at the table.
這我可以給你
And that is something that I can give you.
再次感謝  巴恩斯先生
Thank you again, Mr. Barnes,
謝謝你讓我看
for letting me take a look.
我不忍扔掉任何東西
I just can't seem to throw anything out.
不管情況看起來多糟糕...
No matter how dire things look...
你都能熬出頭的
you're gonna come out of this alive.
-十月早就過了  -確實
- Well, we are way past October. - We certainly are.
我得說  我沒想到這么快就會再來
I must say, I didn't expect to be back here so soon.
我會確保共和黨人
I'll make sure the Republicans
不會維護我的候選人
don't come to my candidate's defense.
但您會勝選
But you're going to win.
你畢竟是安德伍德家的人
You're an Underwood, after all.
將軍竟然說要殺死總統
The general talked about killing the president.
再加上康威在飛機上的爆發
That, along with Conway's outburst on the plane--
這么說好像夸大了實際情況
That sounds worse than it was.
不  實際情況就是這么嚴重
No, that sounds exactly as bad as it was.
讓我覺得驚訝的是
What's surprising to me is...
選舉團隊竟然應對不過來
the campaign couldn't get their hands around this.
哈里·馬歇爾已經很厲害了
I mean, Harry Marshall is as good as they come, but--
他們先是否認  接著又模棱兩可
First they denied, and then they equivocated--
這簡直太荒唐了
I mean, that's just, like, ridiculous.
你站出來
You just come out,
"我道歉  我們說錯話了"
"I apologize. We misspoke."
所有人都知道這套路
Everybody knows the drill here.
共和黨人也沒有沖過去幫他們
And it's not like the Republicans rushed in
力挽狂瀾
to save the day either.
-完全不談正題  -他們默不作聲
- Off message throughout. - They got quiet.
這一點我怎么也想不通
Which I will never understand.
威爾·康威可是黨內冉冉升起的新星
Will Conway was a rising star in the party.
怎么能跟安德伍德政治機器相匹敵呢
Look, it's hard to compete with the Underwood machine.
天啊  我們別再說這些"陰謀占領"的瘋話了
God. Let's not do the whole "black helicopters" crazy stuff.
太荒唐了
It's ridiculous.
我們得接受安德伍德贏得大選這一事實
Look, we need to accept Underwood won the election.
公眾得接受這個結果  繼續前進
People need to accept the outcome and move on.
我同意范的觀點
I'm gonna agree with Van.
我覺得我們應該感激憲法
I think we need to take a moment to appreciate the Constitution.
它會彎折[妥協]It bent,
-但不會折斷[毀壞]  -說得沒錯
- but it never broke. - That's right.
我們都知道  到最后
And in the end, as we all know,
還是由選舉人團決定
it came down to the Electoral College.
你不用說那句話  州長
You don't have to say the words, Governor.
我應該說
I think I do.
恭喜  當選總統先生
Congratulations, Mr. President Elect.
這次沒有稿子嗎
There's no script for this one?
國家第一  先生
Country first, sir.
我很高興你這么說  威爾
I'm glad to hear you say that, Will.
我想幫這個國家愈合
I want to start to help the country heal again.
說完了嗎
Are we done?
說完了  但是威爾
We are done. But Will...
我很想向國家展示
I would very much like to show the country
我們兩黨可以齊心協作
that our two parties can work together.
我希望你考慮
So I was hoping that you might consider
做我的運輸部長
becoming my transportation secretary.
如果你同意加入我的內閣
I think it would send a powerful message
會發出一個強有力的信號
if you agreed to join my cabinet.
你覺得我能
You think I'd...
當好運輸部長嗎
make a good... transportation secretary?
沒錯
Yes.
這是開給無名議員的條件
That's what you give the congressman from nowhere.
我會拒絕的
I'll be declining.
聽到你這么說真是太遺憾了  威爾
Well, I'm so sorry to hear that, Will.
我想祝你一切順利
And I wanted to wish you the very best.
去你的  去你的祝福
You and your wishes can go fuck yourselves!
我現在做什么
What do I do now?
所有人都以為威爾會贏
...everyone thought it would happen.
沒人想到安德伍德還能贏
No one thought that Underwood would win again...
我不知道
I don't know.
承認失敗從來都不容易
Acknowledging defeat is never easy.
在公眾面前承認更是無比煎熬
Doing it in public is a living hell.
起碼媒體喜歡他
Well, at least the cameras like him.
我看著滿意嗎
Do I look satisfied?
你看著還算滿意
You look somewhat satisfied.
-好  -"好"可不夠
- Good. - Not good.
弗蘭西斯  享受這一刻吧
Francis, enjoy this moment.
-這是你應得的  -是"我們"吧
- You deserve it. - You mean "we."
我們成功到達另一邊了
We made it to the other side.
是啊
Yes.
但另一邊有什么
But what is on the other side?
勝利
Victory.
稍帶點失敗的氣息
With a whiff of defeat.
花了好久才走到這一步
It's taken a long time to get here,
但我們到了
but we're here.
干杯  弗蘭西斯
Cheers, Francis.
今后一切都會變得容易
Everything gets easier from now on.
他們準備好了
They're ready for you.
-漢娜  -我不想去
- Hannah. - I don't want to go.
不
No.
好吧
Fine.
那我自己去吧
I'll do it on my own.
要知道  這是個重要時刻
I'm gonna say, this is a crucial moment.
對你們兩個都是
For both of you.
看你們如何應對
How you handle tonight.
黨拋棄了我
The party abandoned me.
你的黨
Your party.
我不是共和黨  威爾
I'm not the Republican Party, Will.
我只為候選人效力
I work for candidates.
我為你效力
I worked for you.
聽好  你輸了
Listen, you lost.
但還有一多半國民
But more than half the country
仍認為你是他們的總統
still considers you their president.
你必須要面對他們
This is what's required.
走出去  發表講話
Go down there, give your speech.
認輸吧
Concede.
我正式接受各位的辭呈
As I accept all of your letters of resignation
并解散我的舊內閣
and dissolve my old cabinet,
然后我想歡迎在座各位加入我的新內閣
I wanna welcome each and every one of you to my new cabinet.
-恭喜你  總統先生  -謝謝  凱茜
- Congratulations, Mr. President. - Thank you, Cathy.
我尤其想感謝我的妻子
And I especially wanna thank my wife.
副總統女士
Madam Vice President...
感謝你對我長期堅定的支持
thank you for your unending and unwavering support.
這一個月來  你的堅強領導維持了國家的運作
Your steady hand kept this country running this past month.
我欠她太多  多到我無法想象
I owe her more than I can possibly fathom.
而她也欠我
And she owes me.
不對  你一直在我身邊支持著我
Not true. You were with me all the way.
作為合法當選總統
I would like to make my first 100 days
我希望我的頭一百天能取得盡可能多的成績
as the duly elected president as productive as possible.
當然  挑戰還是很多的
Of course, there are many challenges.
提振經濟
Shoring up the economy,
保護我國不受哈里發國攻擊
securing our nation from ICO
還要降低失業率
and reducing unemployment.
但我們面對的最艱巨的問題
But the biggest challenge that we face,
也是我最需要各位通力協助的挑戰
and the one that I'm going to need all of your help on,
就是重新團結全國
is reuniting a country
彌合這個國家前所未有的裂痕
that has never been more divided than it is today.
我相信我們可以迎難而上
I believe we can meet this challenge,
而我需要各位的幫助
and that's where I'm gonna need all of your help.
所以今天我們就開始治愈國家
So let's let the healing begin today
共同創造歷史吧
and let's make history together.
感謝你們長久的辛勤奉獻
I thank you all for your continued service.
現在回去工作吧
Now let's get back to work.
我需要一分鐘
I need a minute.
我想我們應該早做打算
I think we should see what we can do
把厄舍趕走
about making Usher persona non grata.
現在開戰不合適吧
I don't think that's wise to start a war.
我們才剛剛拿下白宮
We've just won the White House.
現在才是出手的最佳時機
This is exactly when we should strike.
只有現在我們才有足夠的政治資本
This is a moment that we have the political capital...
厄舍必須小心處理
Usher needs to be managed carefully.
總統先生
Mr. President?
喘口氣吧  道格
Take a breath, Doug.
我們才剛剛站穩腳跟
We've only just landed on our feet here.
先生  副總統女士
Sir, Madam Vice President,
過去在眾議院  這種人就是重點打擊對象
this is the type of person that we used to crucify in the House.
但現在我們不在眾議院  我們在白宮
Yes, but we're not in the House now. We're here.
我們還有一整個任期呢
We have a full term ahead of us.
我們肯定會取得
There's gonna be a great deal
非常多的成就
that we're gonna be able to accomplish,
咱們三個合作
the three of us.
感謝您的器重  先生
I appreciate that, sir.
但是馬克·厄舍早晚會變成麻煩的
But Mark Usher will become a problem.
每個人早晚都會變成麻煩
Well, everyone becomes a problem, eventually.
莉安出局了
LeAnn's out.
什么
What?
為什么
Why?
她搞砸了
She screwed up.
有什么需要我準備的嗎
Well, is it something I need to get ready for?
安德伍德夫婦希望間接處理她
The Underwoods want this handled indirectly.
所以我們具體該說什么
So what exactly are we saying?
她被趕走了
She's being pushed out.
好  但是選舉結束了
Okay, but the campaign's over.
還有必要對外說什么嗎
Is it necessary to say anything?
我們需要撇清本屆政府與她
We need to distance this administration
和她工作的關系
from her and her work.
還有她的策略
Her tactics.
得裝成是泄露出去的
So it needs to be a leak.
泄露給不喜歡我們的人
Reach out to the people who don't like us.
他們肯定樂意爆料
They'll be prime to go with it.
等我們回應的時候
Okay, so when we respond...
-是公開還是  -公開
- On the record or... - On.
她做了什么
What did she do?
她展現出了很差的判斷力
She showed some very poor judgment.
我相信你會謹慎的
I'm trusting you to be discreet.
我們贏了  賽斯
We won, Seth.
需要做出一些改變
Changes need to be made.
你知道我已經遠離政治了
You know I'm off politics.
你來找我  我真的很驚訝
Surprised you reached out to me.
你是一位非常受人尊敬的記者
You're a highly-respected journalist.
就是來參加就職典禮和舞會而已
Just here for the inauguration and the parties.
我想你已經聽說了  我被趕走了
So I imagine you've heard that I'm on the outs.
他們沒有說出全部實情
They're not telling the whole story.
發生了什么
So what happened?
我有個熟人
An acquaintance of mine
從國安局偷了機密文件
stole classified documents from the NSA
去了俄羅斯
and took off to Russia.
他們因為這件事責怪我
They're blaming me for it.
你這個熟人帶走的是什么
What did this acquaintance take?
問題就是這個  我也不知道
That's just the thing. I have no idea.
要是你能找到他  跟他談談
If you could find him, talk to him,
他會告訴你  我和這事一點關系都沒有
he would tell you that I had nothing to do with this.
他是誰  他叫什么
Who is he? What's his name?
艾丹·麥卡倫
Aidan Macallan.
他會跟你談的  他尊重你
He'll talk to you. He respects you.
告訴他我現在沒事
Tell him that I'm okay.
以后也會沒事的
That I'm going to be okay.
我堅信派遣地面部隊
I'm a firm believer in boots on the ground.
我們就是為了石油去的  別裝了
Well, we're there for the oil. Let's not pretend.
我不否認保護原油供應的重要性
I'm not denying how crucial it is to protect the oil supply.
但由我們來盯住
But it's in the world's best interest
對整個世界都好
that we're the ones keeping an eye on it.
-盯住世界還是石油  -都是
- On the world or the oil? - Both.
難怪你對南極那么感興趣
Well, that explains your strong interest in Antarctica.
我確實關注事情和人
I do focus on things and people.
我常會起憐惜之情
I tend to get attached,
但我覺得這讓我的工作更加出色
but I think it makes me better at what I do.
你現在關注什么
And what are you focused on now?
首先是佩特羅夫和艾哈邁德·艾哈邁迪
Petrov. Ahmed Al Ahmadi. To begin with.
抱歉
I'm... I'm sorry.
我只是
I just...
我明天再問你的意見
I'll run this by you tomorrow.
好  明天
Yes, tomorrow.
抱歉打斷你們了
Sorry for the interruption.
他是我們的一個演講撰稿人
He's one of our speechwriters.
湯姆·耶茨很有名
Tom Yates has quite a reputation.
要是他的書能說明什么的話
Well, if his books are any indication,
他的生活可很精彩
he has lived quite a life.
我爸爸也穿條紋襪
My father wore striped socks.
你覺得總統會贊同我們的議程嗎
Do you think the president will be sympathetic to our agenda?
"我們的議程"  這么說太自負了
"Our agenda"? That's very presumptuous.
這世界上有些地區
Well, there are regions in the world
對我們的國家安全很重要
that are important to our national security
我們必須保護這些地區
and they have to be protected.
你想跟我們一起參加就職舞會嗎
Would you like to join us at the inaugural ball?
不行
Oh, no, I can't.
只要我去舞會  就會發生可怕的事
Something terrible always happens when I go to a party.
順說  我丈夫不會受任何人的擺布
By the way, my husband is not managed by anyone.
-我不是這個意思  -不是嗎
- That's not what I'm asking. - Isn't it?
我是想讓你幫忙  副總統女士
I'm asking for your help, Madam Vice President.
僅此而已
That is all.
晚上好
Evening.
天啊  進來吧
Oh, my God. Come in.
抱歉  坐吧  坐吧
I'm sorry. Sit down, sit down.
今晚不鍛煉了嗎
Aren't we working out tonight?
我應該是沒時間了
I just don't think I'm gonna have the time for it.
過來坐一會兒
But come sit for a minute.
要是你太忙的話
If you're too busy,
-我能理解  -不  來跟我坐會兒
- I understand-- - No, no. Join me for a minute.
我想讓你聽點東西
I want you to hear something.
"這是新時代的黎明
"This is the dawn of a new era.
這是和平的時代
It's a time for peace.
要尊重過去  擁抱未來
A time to respect the past and embrace the future.
要..."
A time..."
要什么
Time to what?
"要聆聽所有聲音
"A time to hear all the voices.
因為世間最大的孤獨
For there is nothing more lonely...
恐怖
or terrifying...
便是無人聆聽"
than feeling unheard."
你覺得怎么樣
What do you think?
有意思  我喜歡
It's interesting. I like it.
-這是為了  -我的就職典禮  沒錯
- This is for... - My inauguration, yes.
然后呢  你接下去怎么說
Where does it go from there? What do you say?
"美國人民  我聽到了你們的聲音
"America, I hear you.
無論你們是否投票給了我
Whether you voted for me or not,
我聽到了你們所有人的聲音"
I hear all of you."
你覺得我的曾曾曾祖父
Now, what do you think my great-great-great-grandfather
會怎么評價這些
would think of all this?
令人敬畏[非常好]
Awesome.
-就這詞原本的意思  -是啊
- In the original sense of the word. - Yeah.
你要在這兒待多久
How long you in town for?
實際上  今晚就走
Leaving tonight, actually.
我以為你是來參加就職典禮的
I thought you were here for the inauguration.
我收到了一條消息  得走了
I got a tip I have to move on.
什么消息
What's the tip?
咱們以前對工作談話可是有規矩的
We used to have a rule about shoptalk.
是嗎
Did we?
好吧
Fair enough.
你怎么看莉安·哈維
What's your read on LeAnn Harvey?
她很難看透  這也是我喜歡她之處
That she's hard to read. That's what I like about her.
你信任她
You trust her?
凱特  拜托
Kate, come on.
你很憔悴
You look tired.
我現在一周工作八天
I'm working eight days a week.
你以前也總是很憔悴的樣子
I mean, you always looked tired,
但你現在的憔悴  不那么性感了
but now you look tired in a... not sexy way.
抱歉讓你失望了
Sorry to disappoint.
其實我馬上就得回去了
I actually have to get back there in a minute.
這會兒回辦公室有點晚了吧
It's little late to head back to the office, right?
我從上周二起就一直在那邊
I've been there since last Tuesday.
說實話
Honestly...
我知道這話聽起來有點怪
I know this sounds weird...
但我沒有更想去的地方了
There's no place I'd rather be.
你這話的語氣真...生硬
The way you say that sounds so... rote.
我說不好
I don't know...
這讓我怎么回應
What am I supposed to say to that?
我只想知道你好不好  僅此而已
I just want to know how you're doing, that's all.
我只是關心你  坐在我眼前的這個人
I'm just asking about you, this person I'm sitting with.
你想什么呢  湯姆·耶茨
Where'd you go, Tom Yates?
我找你來著
I was looking for you.
看來找得不夠用心啊
Not very hard, then.
我得跟你談談
I need to talk to you.
好
Okay.
我不干了
I'm done.
我不想再寫演講稿了
With the speechwriting, I don't want to do it anymore.
我想回去做我之前在做的其他事
I want to get back to some other stuff I was working on.
沒別的意思  我知道寫演講稿也是寫作
No offense. I mean, I know writing speeches is writing...
但這不是我真正想做的
but it's not what I really wanna do.
好
Okay.
你確定
You sure?
是的
Yes.
我們會把你調出去的
We'll transition you out.
但你以后再來就得想好借口了
But you'll need to have a reason to be here.
特別顧問  你逗我嗎
Special advisor? Are you kidding me?
有猜測說他已經...
There's speculation that he's already...
這不是猜測  賽斯
It's not speculation, Seth.
人們知道馬克·厄舍在某種程度上為我們工作
People know that Mark Usher is working for us in some capacity.
-那還不夠嗎  -把發布寫得好一點
- I mean, isn't that enough? - Clean up this release.
突破黨派界限之類的
Uh, reaching across party lines, that sort of thing.
-準備好  以防萬一  -當然
- And get it ready, just in case. - Of course.
就這樣
That's it.
我知道你不高興
I know you're not happy about this.
他憑什么能贏得那頭銜
What has he done to earn the title?
這不是他贏得什么的問題
This is not about him earning anything.
他已經在接觸機密備忘錄了
He's already getting classified memos.
她為什么想這樣
Why does she want this?
"她"
"She"?
抱歉  我是說副總統
I'm sorry. The vice president.
她想要的是讓這個政府成功
What she wants is for this administration to succeed.
而我想要的是你跟他成為朋友  了解他
And what I want is for you to befriend him. Get to know him.
我們要讓他以為是他在操控我們
We want him to think he's managing us
而其實是我們在控制他
while we're busy managing him.
她追查弗蘭西斯·安德伍德很久了
She has been pursuing Francis Underwood for a long time.
-我不想和她談  -艾丹
- I don't wanna talk to her. - Aidan...
她怎么知道我在這兒的
How does she even know I'm here?
鮑德溫女士是個非常優秀的記者
Miss Baldwin is a very good journalist.
把事情公開對你和我都沒幫助
Yeah, going public will not help you, or me.
你就跟她說說  你是怎么操縱美國民意的
You'll tell her how you manipulated the American mood, hmm?
-你是怎么偷走大選勝利的  -那我就完了
- How you helped steal an election. - That would be it for me.
你可是我們俄羅斯聯邦的貴客
You're a valued guest of the Russian state.
我想要回我的護照
I want my passport back.
美國護照是絕對保護不了你的
An American passport is the last thing that will keep you safe.
我愿賭一把
I'll take my chances.
這下你要出名了  當個告密者
This will make you famous, hmm? A whistle-blower.
我不想出名
I don't wanna be famous.
但你想要自由
But you do want to be free.
你光飯錢就花了一萬五
You spent $15,000 at The Capital Grille?
你吃金子嗎
What the fuck are you eating?
-這是羅梅洛利用紀律委員會  -這是把柄
- This is Romero using the House Ethics... - It's a liability.
你就不該犯這種錯
And you should know better.
這事你怎么沒說過  泰瑞
How did you not disclose this, Terry?
我想把他踢出委員會
I want to pull him off his committee assignments.
扔進科學委員會  看他喜不喜歡宇航局報告
Put him on Science. See how he likes NASA briefings.
先緩緩吧
I'd like to hold off on that.
羅梅洛就要成為總統的親密盟友了
Romero's about to become an ally to the president.
怎么會呢
And why's that?
因為他能查出你的賬單有問題
Because he was able to find out about your tab.
因為他從不輕易放手
It's because he's relentless.
因為四年后亞利桑那州35%的選民是拉丁裔
Because in four years, 35% of the vote in Arizona will be Latino.
因為他就是未來
Because he's the future.
就是這么開始的
This is how it starts.
我得回國會去了
I gotta get back to the Hill.
跟你說  道格
You know, Doug...
你我都待得夠久  見過換護衛
you and I, we've been around long enough to see the guard change.
之所以會換人  是因為上頭那些人
And it changes because the people at the top
忘了自己是怎么爬上去的
forget how they got there.
羅梅洛也想換護衛  道格
Romero's trying to change the guard, Doug.
而我們就是護衛
And we are the guard.
要是烏麥克議員無所隱瞞
If Congressman Womack has nothing to hide,
那他就沒什么好怕的
he has nothing to fear.
我們都有要隱瞞的事  羅梅洛議員
We all have something to hide, Congressman Romero.
領導層該換人了
It's time for a change in the leadership.
總統想當你的朋友
The president would like to be a friend to you,
但你讓他很難做
but you're making it very difficult.
我們可以保證移民禁令
We can guarantee the immigration ban
下星期就會取消
will be lifted in the next week.
拜托  又來這一套嗎
Come on. Are we doing this again?
你開個種族歧視的條件
You offer me some racist gesture.
我怎么  就當死黨嗎  本來你也禁不住
And I, what? I'm a friend forever? Ban isn't even sustainable.
你最在乎的究竟是什么
What matters to you?
-總統的注意力  -你有啊
- The president's attention. - You have it.
-全部的注意力  -你過分了
- His full attention... - You know, that's enough.
你到底想要什么
What is it that you really want?
我想要醫保覆蓋率調回原來的水平
I want Medicare coverage bumped up to where it was.
我的選區有不少退休工人
There are retirees in my district.
你見我就只想要擴大醫保嗎
We're here now because you want a bump in Medicare?
得了吧  議員
Come on, Congressman.
還有兩個就職典禮的座位
And two seats to the inauguration.
-就剩兩天了  -講臺座位
- We are two days out. - On the dais.
你的算盤完全打錯了
You are going about this entirely wrong.
是你主動來找我  是你求我
You came here. You asked me.
我告訴你
I'm telling you.
我就想看弗蘭西斯·安德伍德當著我的面
I want to be there when Francis Underwood says to me
宣布提高醫保水平
that there will be an increase in Medicare.
只要他一句話  我就是他鐵哥們
He does that, I'm his friend.
那我現在就可以代表總統
Well, I think I speak for the president
告訴你這事根本不可能
when I say that's not going to happen.
斯坦普先生  我真的很欽佩你為他做的一切
Mr. Stamper, I really appreciate all the work you do for him,
但你我都知道我的黨團在擴大
but you and I know that my bloc is growing.
我只要求他在就職講話里說句話
All I'm looking for is a line in his address.
兩個座位  一句話
Two seats and a line.
-好大的膽子  -我告訴他基本沒可能
- The balls on him. - I told him it was highly doubtful.
我可以再回去正式拒絕他
I can get back to him with a firm no.
或者你可以答應他提一句
Or you could give him a line.
他的保證很不可靠
His promises are unreliable.
我了解艾力克斯  我們在康威競選時見過面
Look, I know Alex. We met on Conway's campaign.
只要他加入  就一定死心塌地
Once he's in, he's in.
總統先生  我們得謹慎決定要給出什么條件
Sir, we have to be very careful with what we're giving away.
他能給政府帶來
He's capable of giving this administration
巨大的困擾
an enormous amount of grief.
他只是想讓我們對他示好
He's asking for a gesture.
要我說可不止
Oh, I'd say it's a little more than that.
完全同意  他想找幫我們獲勝的人的麻煩
I completely agree. He's going after the people who got us here.
他并沒有錯  對嗎
He's not wrong, is he?
有些領導層的人確實該下臺了
There are some in leadership whose time has come and gone.
瞧  我是來確保
Look... I'm just here to make sure
你能連任的
your four years turn into eight, but...
但決定權還是在你手上
it's up to you, of course.
他要的不過是兩個座位  一句話
But we're talking about two seats... one line...
答應他的要求
Give him what he wants.
艾力克斯
Alex.
蒂爾達  很高興見到你
Tilda. It's lovely to see you.
-你好嗎  議員  -挺好的
- How are you, Congressman? - Oh, I'm fine.
很高興你們都來了  今天是個大日子
It's good of you all to be here. It's a big day.
要不你們坐我的位子
Listen, why don't the two of you take my seats?
謝了  我們已經被安排在走道旁了
Oh, thanks, but we're already on the aisle.
你們務必收下
I insist.
這樣總統說到你想聽的話時
You'll be right in the president's line of vision when he...
你正好能與他對視
says what you want to hear.
請吧  我在哪都行
Please. I can be anywhere.
好吧
Okay.
-謝謝你  馬克  -別客氣
- Thank you, Mark. - Sure.
我  弗蘭西斯·安德伍德  莊嚴宣誓
I, Francis J. Underwood, do solemnly swear...
我必忠實執行...
That I will faithfully execute...
合眾國總統職務
The office of President of the United States.
合眾國總統...是的  這一幕似曾相識
The office of Pres-- Yes, here we go again.
國務卿  那時我是想要這個位子
Secretary of State. That's what I wanted.
我只想要這個位子  也是當時許諾給我的
That's all I wanted. That's what I was promised.
而現在  瞧瞧我
And now, here I am,
成了美國總統
President of these United States.
美國人民  這是你們促成的
You made this bed, America.
是你們投票給我的
You voted for me.
困惑嗎
Are you confused?
害怕嗎
Are you afraid?
因為你以為的夢想成真了
Because what you thought you wanted is now here.
現在你在看著我
And there you are, staring back,
目瞪口呆  一頭霧水
slack-jawed, bewildered,
心想這究竟是不是你們想要的
wondering if this is what you actually asked for.
是民主  你們的民主選擇了我
This democracy, your democracy, elected me.
如果你覺得走到今天實屬不易
And if you think it was hard getting here,
你就能開始明白為了保住權位我會不惜一切
you're beginning to understand what I'm willing to do to stay.
我一眼望向擁擠的人群
I look across at this crowd gathered today
我很清楚他們不是我的支持者
and I know that these are not my supporters.
我看到的是一群臉上掛著微笑
I'm looking at people who are waiting,
等待著自己的機會來臨的人
with a smile on their face, for their turn.
那些笑得最開懷
And the most vicious among them
鼓掌最熱烈的人  也是其中最陰險的
are the ones who are smiling and clapping the hardest.
權力正如房地產  還記得嗎
Power is a lot like real estate. Remember?
-愿上帝助我  -愿上帝助我
- So help me God. - So help me God.
美國人民  我聽到了你們的聲音
America, I hear you.
我聽到了你們所有人的聲音
I hear all your voices.
我聽到了你們的掙扎  你們的擔憂
I hear your struggles, your concerns,
但最重要的是  我聽到了你們的希望
but most of all, I hear your hope.
每個人都希望得到機會和保障
Opportunity and security is what we all want.
所以在我上任后的百天之內  我會團結兩黨
And in my first 100 days, I will reach across party lines
讓我的政府  也是你們的政府
and devote my administration, your government,
保障你們的需要
to securing them.
老年人以及他們所依賴的
For too long we have ignored
醫療保險已經被我們忽視了太久
our seniors and the healthcare they depend on.
所以我要致力于改善醫保政策
That is why I am committed to fixing Medicare
取得成效前  我不會增加一毛錢預算
before I devote one more dime to the program.
《美就法》只是個開始
AmWorks was only the beginning.
我們得學會不再依賴福利津貼
We have to learn to live without entitlements,
因為我們不是不勞而獲的民族
because we are not an entitled people.
我相信你們的每一滴汗水  每一分耕耘
I believe in your sweat. I believe in your hard work.
我今天要向大家承諾的  就是就業機會
And a job, that's what I'll promise you today.
你連一句話都不能給他嗎
You couldn't give him one line?
對不忠誠的人我們一個子也不會給
We give no quarter to those that are disloyal.
今天傳達的信息不是針對他一人
The message sent today wasn't just for him.
-報仇會燃起艾力克斯的斗志  -我也是
- Alex feeds off of retribution. - So do I.
-他值得你引戰嗎  -沒有中間地帶
- Is he worth the fight? - There is no neutrality.
我要求完全的忠誠  不然你就是我的敵人
I expect total loyalty or you are an enemy.
明白了  總統先生
Understood, Mr. President.
你怎么想
What are you thinking?
BGM: My Country, 'Tis of Thee
又稱《America》  愛國歌曲
曾是默認的美國國歌
*讓人民發出聲音*
*Let mortal tongues awake*
*讓人民暢快呼吸*
*Let all that breathe partake*
*讓人民打破沉默*
*Let rocks their silent break*
我就是喜歡這些愛國的東西
I have a soft spot for that patriotic stuff.
請伸開手臂  岔開腿
Please spread your arms and legs.
什么
Excuse me?
否則  別想采訪
Otherwise, there is no interview.
還有  請你脫掉外套
And if you would please take off your jacket.
-我是個記者  -我知道
- I'm a journalist. - I know.
我住在倫敦時讀過你的報道
I read you when I was living in London.
-我不是間諜  -我知道
- So I'm not a spy. - I know you're not a spy.
現在還有人用那個詞嗎
Does anyone even use that word anymore?
采訪不會在這里進行
So the interview won't be happening here.
-我們說好的  -我們得帶你去另一個地方
- Uh, we agreed... - We need to move you to another location.
對不起  你不能用自己的人
Oh, and I'm sorry, you cannot use your own crew.
-這不可接受  -那采訪就得推遲
- That's unacceptable. - Then the interview will have to wait.
我們不能信任你們的人
We cannot trust your people.
你也不想讓麥卡倫先生有危險吧
And you wouldn't want to endanger Mr. Macallan, would you?
你來嗎  鮑德溫女士
Are you coming, Miss Baldwin?
你的手機得留下
And your cell phone needs to stay here.
謝謝
Thank you.
支持你的人很多
You have a lot of support out there,
不管總統說了  或沒說什么
no matter what the president did or didn't say.
有很多人樂意跟你合作
There are people eager to work with you.
我該告訴你
I should tell you...
我要煽動共和黨人
I'm encouraging the Republicans
重啟宣戰委員會
to restart the Declaration of War Committee,
調查總統
to investigate the president.
這很大膽
That's bold.
-我并不是想打動你  -很冒險
- I'm not trying to impress you with that. - It's risky.
你不想跟白宮的人為敵
You don't want an enemy in the White House.
但你現在在白宮了
But you're in the White House now.
你對我是什么
And you're what to me?
讓我幫你吧
Why don't you let me help you?
不非得讓其他人輸你才能贏
Everybody doesn't have to lose for you to win, right?
肖恩·杰弗瑞斯在嗎
Is Sean Jeffries there?
-誰找他  -你是誰
- Who's calling? - Who's this?
我為湯姆·漢默施密特工作
I work for Tom Hammerschmidt.
我不明白為什么把我轉接給你
I don't understand why I was transferred to you.
接待員是我的朋友  我認識他  她認識他
The receptionist is a friend of mine. I know him. She knows him.
我已經聯系他一天了
Well, I've been trying to reach him all day.
我可以替你捎話
I can take a message.
不用  我晚點再打吧
No, I'll try him later.
他已經不在這里工作了
Look, he doesn't work here anymore, so...
-我是他女朋友  -沒事的
- I'm his girlfriend. - That's all right.
-你是誰  -算了
- Who is this? - Don't worry about it.
我是賽斯·格雷森  我有料給你
Hey, it's Seth Grayson. I've got something for you.
莉安·哈維  要被趕走了
LeAnn Harvey, she's being pushed out.
嗯  她出局了
Yeah, she's out.
到了現在  你是唯一
Yeah, well, you're the only one
還得從我這兒聽來的人了
that's got me telling you at this point.
好吧  我正在寫發布稿
Okay. I'm writing the release right now.
好  再見
All right, bye.
我是賽斯·格雷森
Hey, it's Seth Grayson.
我有料給你
Yeah, I got something for you.
凱特·鮑德溫的人本來都準備好了
Kate Baldwin's people were ready to go,
但俄聯邦安全局換掉了她的人
but the FSB replaced the crew.
你牙上有東西
You have something on your tooth.
我們知道他們要去哪嗎
Do we know where they were going?
不  但他們還在受追蹤
No, but they're still being tracked.
凱特·鮑德溫就不該跟他說上話
Kate Baldwin was never supposed to talk to him.
-這采訪絕不能進行  -我們還有時間
- This interview cannot happen. - We still have time.
不  沒有了
No, we don't.
我們得介入
We need to go in.
這可能會產生難以預料的后果
And there might be some unforeseen consequences.
我覺得艾丹不會透露任何
I don't think Aidan would reveal anything
會傷害我  或其他人的信息
that would endanger me... or anyone else.
你跟他的交情有多久
How far back do you and he go?
很久
Far.
僅此而已
That's all.
很遺憾要如此結局
I'm sorry it has to end this way.
我不需要你的同情
I don't need your sympathy.
你快好了
You almost ready?
該死  我找不到我的F了
God damn it. I can't find my "F."
肯定是被人偷了
Someone must have stolen it.
肯定還會找到的
I'm sure it will turn up somewhere.
湯姆  你這身禮服真帥
Tom, you look very handsome in a tuxedo.
我裝作撐得起禮服的人
I act like a man that can wear a tuxedo
我突然就撐得起禮服了
and suddenly I'm a man who can wear a tuxedo.
先用這個湊合吧
This should do for now.
-我剛看到艾瑞克·羅林斯來了  -是啊
- I just saw that Eric Rawlings arrived. - Yes.
湯姆  我們過會兒在樓下跟你碰頭
Tom, we'll meet you downstairs in just a few minutes.
好
Sure.
斯坦普說  我們一小時后就能有
Stamper tells me that we'll have a bead on Macallan's location
麥卡倫下落的線索了
in about an hour or so.
我剛跟簡·戴維斯說了話  她的聯絡人準備好了
I just spoke to Jane Davis. Her contacts are ready and waiting.
我們能撇清關系  弗蘭西斯
We'll have distance, Francis.
我們會欠她的
We'll owe her.
你很帥  很有總統氣質
You look very beautiful. Presidential.
你才美  有副總統的氣質
You look beautiful. Vice Presidential.
就是這晚  佐伊被殺的那晚
Here we are. The night of Zoe's death.
你覺得那是誰
Who does that look like to you?
一個等列車的普通白人
Just another white guy waiting for the train.
看仔細點
Look closer.
我知道你覺得那是誰  但我不能確定
I know who you think it might be, but... I'm really not sure.
關上門
Yeah, shut that door.
杰拉德·福特的兒子以前會
Gerald Ford's son used
偷偷溜上這些樓梯  去屋頂
to sneak up these stairs to go to the roof,
跟朋友演奏齊柏林飛艇
play Led Zeppelin to his friends.
少年就是少年  不管他在哪
Teenagers are teenagers, doesn't matter where.
這是
And this...
維克多·佩特羅夫摁滅雪茄的地方
is where Viktor Petrov put out his cigar.
那人似乎很不好對付
That guy seems like a real piece of work.
相信我  他的確是
Oh, believe me, he is.
你也是
So are you.
這就未必了
No, I don't know about that.
-你干什么  -對不起
- What are you doing? - Oh, I'm sorry.
你為什么說對不起
And what are you sorry about?
我以為你想要一樣  你并不想要的東西
I thought you wanted something that you don't.
你覺得我想要什么
So what is it that you think I wanted?
我們可以再上去  我真的...
We can go back up. I'm... I'm really s...
據說  人體最脆弱的部分
You know, they say the most vulnerable part of the human body...
是喉嚨
is the throat...
你要想真正知道自己對某人的感覺
and that you never really know how you feel about somebody...
就需要那人掐著你的喉嚨
until they have their hands around your throat.
告訴我
So tell me.
你現在什么感覺
How do you feel now?
恭喜  總統先生
Congratulations, Mr. President.
以免我忘了  莉安·哈維讓我跟你打招呼
Before I forget, LeAnn Harvey wanted me to say hello.
她怎么樣
How is she?
她要我告訴你
Well, she wanted me to tell you
她沒事  她不會有事
that she's... she's all right. She's gonna be all right.
那是什么意思
What does that mean?
她現在  請假了
She's, um, taking a leave of absence.
至少他們是這么說的
Well, that's what they're calling it,
但看來
but it... it seems that
她被趕出政府了
she's being pushed out of the administration.
是她告訴我你在這兒的
She's the one who told me you were here.
叫我來跟你談談
Suggested I talk to you.
莉安雇了你  是吧
LeAnn hired you, isn't that right?
家族朋友
Friend of the family?
對  我們這就開始采訪了嗎
Yeah, um, are we starting the interview now?
不不  我們就聊聊  但應該就好了
No, no. We're just talking. But we should be ready soon.
對不起  我能...
I'm sorry. Can I, uh...
我們開始前  我能單獨待會兒嗎
Can I just have a second before we start?
-可以  當然  -好
- I think so. Sure. Um... - Okay.
我去...喘口氣
Yeah. I'm... I'm gonna need some air.
不  我就回來
No, I just... I just need a second, okay?
好啊  去喘氣吧
Of course. Get some air.
好
Okay.
我想借你的手機
I want your phone.
我想借你的手機  拿著
I need your phone. Take this.
一通電話
One call.
就一通
One.
喂
Hello?
莉安  是我
LeAnn, it's me.
天吶  艾丹
My God, Aidan.
我知道你有麻煩了  我們這么辦
I know you're in trouble. Here's the plan.
拿支筆  記下這號碼
All right. Get a pen. Write down this number.
他是個律師  他可以幫你出國
He... he's a lawyer. He can get you out of the country.
等你到了俄羅斯  我就能保護你
Once you're in Russia, I can protect you.
對不起
I'm sorry.
為什么
Why?
他們還有多久會找到我
How long do I have before they come and get me?
他們就在外面
They're right outside.
如果我跑呢
And if I run?
會有人受傷  你不會想那么做的
Uh, people will get hurt. You don't want to do that.
我喜歡德州
I like Texas.
或許是因為陽光或塵土
Maybe it's the sun or the dust,
但人們打招呼時都會瞇著眼
but people kind of squint when they say hello.
我一直喜歡那樣
I always liked that.
我就不該走的
I never should've left.
你一直對我很好
You've always been very good to me.
我喜歡你媽媽
I liked your mother.
我很喜歡她
I liked her a lot.
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
不必
Don't be.
二樓有個守衛是我們的人
There's a guard on the second floor working with us.
他會護送你去個角落  有出租車在等著你
He'll escort you to a corner where a cab will be waiting.
會有人給你開門
Someone will open the door. Just...
上車就行
get in.
你不想念德州嗎
So you don't miss Texas?
不  我想
No, I do.
我想獲得安寧
I'm trying to find some peace with this
而你在幫倒忙
and you're not helping.
-就再問幾個問題  -我要搬走了
- Just a couple more questions. - I'm moving, you know.
-我得到了新工作  -巴恩斯先生
- I got a new job... - Mr. Barnes?
他們將你女兒的死判為意外
They ruled your daughter's death an accident.
我開始有所懷疑了
I am starting to doubt that.
-我們能不能再說一兩遍  -知道嗎
- Could we just go over one or two more... - You know what?
我不能再這么下去了
I just can't keep doing this.
別再給我打電話了
Stop calling me, please.
采訪不會進行了
The interview will not be happening.
會有人護送你回酒店
Someone will escort you back to your hotel.
總統先生
Mr. President.
希望我沒來得太晚
I hope I'm not too late to the party.
你正好趕上隆重登場
I'd say you were just in time to make your grand entrance.
這一切開始時  我可沒想過
Well, when all this started, I don't think I imagined myself
今晚會跟你一起站在這里
standing here with you tonight.
-再次恭喜你  總統先生  -謝謝
- Congratulations, Mr. President. Again. - Oh, thank you.
我要等你嗎
Um, should I wait for you?
不用  舞會上見
No, no. I'll see you inside the party.
那么  羅梅洛如何了
So... how's Romero?
羅梅洛想讓共和黨人
Well, Romero wants to get the Republicans
重啟宣戰委員會
to restart the Declaration of War Committee.
好一份就職大禮
What a lovely inauguration gift.
別說你感到意外
Don't tell me you're surprised.
我沒有
I'm not.
里面見  去喝一杯吧
I'll see you inside. Get a drink.
你可真美
Well, don't you look stunning.
這一晚很漫長  弗蘭克
It's been a long night, Frank.
我得回家了
I need to get home.
得了  賞個臉吧
Come on. Do me the honor.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
道格  打扮得真帥
Doug! Don't you look good.
謝謝您  副總統女士
Thank you, Madam Vice President.
你見到弗蘭西斯了嗎
Have you seen Francis?
好一會兒沒見著了  女士
Not for a little while, no, ma'am.
大家在紛紛離開了
Well, the party's breaking up.
我想讓他來跟人道別
I want him to say goodbye to people.
-好  女士  我去找他  -道格
- Yes, ma'am. I'll let him know. - Doug?
我有個問題問你  就一件小事
I have a question for you. Just a small thing.
-怎么了  -你怎么沒去看砍頭
- What is it? - Why weren't you at the beheading?
-什么  -詹姆斯·米勒被砍頭那晚
- What? - The night James Miller was beheaded.
我們都在  我們四個
We were all there, the four of us.
弗蘭西斯  湯姆  莉安和我
Francis, Tom, LeAnn and myself.
你怎么不在
Why not you?
你見到弗蘭西斯  就說我找他
You see Francis, tell him I'm looking for him.
是  女士
Yes, ma'am.
我以為你迷路了
I thought you got lost.
不  我就想歇歇
No. I just needed a break.
我們要去跟客人道別嗎
Shall we bid our guests farewell?
不  今晚還早呢
No, the night is young.
看我找到了什么
Look what I found.
他們要重啟委員會
They're restarting the committee.
我以為我們扼殺了那個委員會
I thought we killed that committee.
眾議院什么都野火燒不盡
Nothing ever really dies in the House.
只不過關注的人越來越少
It just plays in front of a smaller and smaller audience.
-這事可不小  -我知道
- This is serious. - I know.
但我們還是好好享受舞會吧
But let's enjoy the rest of the party.
你是做什么的
What do you do here?
我為他們工作
I work for them.
總統讓我確保你安全回家
The president asked me to make sure that you get home safely.
我給你安排了一輛車
I have a car for you.
我還想多待一會兒
I thought I'd stay a little while longer.
總統明天早上要早起
The president has an early morning tomorrow.
這邊請
Right this way.
那個導游
The tour guide?
-什么  -是的
- What?  - Yes.
搞什么  我應該拿那個導游怎么辦呢
WTF. What am I supposed to do about the tour guide?
還在媒體接待室  湯姆  不是吧
The press briefing room, Tom, really?
我以為沒人會在意
I didn't think anyone would care.
那我是該留下她還是讓她走人呢
Well, should I... keep her on or let her go?
她這樣做是很不專業的
I mean, it was rather unprofessional on her part.
她很擅長她的工作
She's good at her job.
湯姆...
Tom...
不要對我妻子不忠
don't cheat on my wife.
巴恩斯先生
Mr. Barnes?
你想到別的地方喝杯咖啡嗎
Do you want to get a coffee somewhere away from this?
我一直在想你說的話
I keep thinking about what you said.
我在她的東西中找到了這個
I found this with her things.
父親節那天
It was Father's Day...
是我最后一次跟她通話
the last time I heard from her.
我們不是很親近
We weren't close.
我很驚訝她會打電話給我
I was surprised she called.
我當然很開心  但是...
I mean, I was happy, of course, but...
我能留著這個嗎
Can I hold on to this?
我不知道
I didn't know...
她有麻煩了
that she was in trouble.
當警察問我她是不是有自殺傾向的時候
When the police asked if i thought she was suicidal,
我說  "可能吧"
I said, "Maybe."
我并不了解她
I didn't know her, really.
我也是
Neither did I.
我會調查這個的
I'll look into this.
好
Okay.
謝謝你
Thank you.
政治新聞網  《早安喬》上說了五分鐘
Politico. Five minutes on Morning Joe.
發新聞稿真的有必要嗎
Was a press release really necessary?
你要去休假
You're taking a leave.
新聞稿上說你要休假
The press release said that you were taking a leave
來考慮一下你的職業選擇
to consider your career options.
得看上去像真的才行  你知道的
This has to look real. You know that.
如果他們要和我見面怎么辦
What if they need to meet with me?
那他們就會和你見面
Then they'll meet with you.
我可以叫保安護送你出去
I could have security escort you out.
那么既然現在厄舍是特別顧問了
So since Usher is special advisor now,
那你又算什么呢
where does that leave you?
我說過了  如果有需要  他們會給打你的
Like I said, they'll call you if they need you.
我可以成為你的朋友的  知道嗎
I can be a friend to you, you know.
不必這樣的
It doesn't have to be like this.
我沒有朋友
I don't have any friends.
我把他安排在了巴黎的約旦大使館
I landed him at the Jordanian Embassy in Paris.
我們計劃什么時候把他弄出來
When do we plan to get him out?
據我所知  現在還不知道
Well, as I understand it, you don't yet know
麥卡倫先生可能告訴了佩特羅夫總統些什么
what Mr. Macallan may have told President Petrov.
我要麥卡倫回來  越快越好
I want Macallan back here sooner rather than later.
這些事不發生在美國境內會更好些
It's better if these things don't happen on American soil.
是  但我決定了
Yes, but I make those decisions.
當然  總統先生
Of course, Mr. President.
請放心
And rest assured,
這件事是查不到你們身上的
neither of your fingerprints are anywhere near this.
我們怎么處理莉安
So what do we do about LeAnn?
她參與了選舉舞弊  天吶
She's been involved in election fraud, for Christ's sake.
她犯了很多錯
She's made a lot of mistakes.
是的  但很多人都犯過
Yes, but lots of people have.
話是那么說  但有些人就走到頭了
Yes, but some people run their course.
如今真難知道能相信誰
It's hard to know who to trust these days.
可不是嘛
Isn't it?
美國聯邦政府內閣包括副總統在內  目前共24名成員
其中負責國家安全的  如國務卿  國土安全部長  國防部長  被認為最重要
此外司法部長  財務部長也是比較重要的位置
而交通部長  農業部長  教育部長等  被認為是相對次要的職位
但因為現任總統特朗普在競選時承諾
上任后將進行總值1萬億美元的基礎建設投資
所以交通部長在現政府中地位較高
現任交通部長是華裔趙小蘭  她丈夫麥康諾是參議院多數黨領袖
許多媒體認為  特朗普任命趙小蘭負責交通部
除了因她在小布什政府任職時  表現優異之外
也可能是希望在基建政策上獲得麥康諾的支持
"醫保改革"過去八年來一直是美國政治斗爭的核心議題
奧巴馬的新醫保法案在2010年通過后
就一直遭右翼政客及共和黨選民的反對
共和黨也借此先后奪回了國會兩院的控制權
特朗普競選時  一再承諾上臺后會推翻和替代原有的醫保法案
但上任后  實際操作卻困難重重  現在的替代法案能否通過尚無定數
同時  現有的醫保制度在美國社會遇到了大麻煩
2009年推行法案時  奧巴馬稱法案通過后  保費會大幅降低
但法案施行后  不僅保費年年暴漲  而且由于醫保公司虧損嚴重
在進入2017年后  美國一些地區的百姓已經無法購買"奧巴馬醫保"
所以替代方案也是勢在必行了